# YANELY RAMIREZ

**USER EXPERIENCE TECHNOLOGIST** 



## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

User Experience Specialist, Web Developer, and Designer.

#### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

	UX & UI	Programming
<ul> <li>Design Research</li> <li>Interaction Design</li> <li>Rapid Prototyping</li> <li>User Research</li> <li>Usability Testing</li> <li>Wireframe</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>User-Centered Design Methods</li> <li>Customer Journey Maps</li> <li>Personas</li> <li>Figma</li> <li>Adobe XD</li> <li>Photoshop &amp; Illustrator</li> </ul>	<ul><li>HTML5</li><li>CSS3</li><li>Javascript</li><li>JSON</li><li>JIRA</li><li>Git</li></ul>

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SECURITY FIRST INSURANCE, 2018 - PRESENT

#### **USER EXPERIENCE SPECIALIST II**, 2020 - Present

- Designed and launched the company's <u>customer portal</u>, migrating from legacy vendor platform to a new vendor platform (cutting costs, upheld tight deadlines, redesigned to adhere to latest brand guidelines, and improved customer experience).
- Acts as point of contact and collaborates with key stakeholders including business analysts, business owners, and project manager throughout projects.
- Presents design solutions to leadership team to get their buy-in or gather feedback.
- Works in a team to create compelling user experiences along with designs that are showcased on Adobe XD or Figma via wireframes and high-fidelity mockups. Improved customer communications by updating content to be personalized to the reader while focusing on brand tone, loyalty, and customer satisfaction.
- Utilized Mailchimp and collaborated with other team members to create time-sensitive email marketing campaigns coordinating with events and product launches to increase profits.
- Use data and research to define web experiences for customer-facing platforms using design best practices.

## **USER EXPERIENCE SPECIALIST**, 2018 - 2020

- Collaborated with Taoti, web agency, to update the <u>company website</u> to adhere to brand guidelines, improve tone of the organization. Attended war rooms, outlining the characteristics of the brand using mood boards to establish brand guidelines.
- Partnered with stakeholders across the organization to identify & prioritize customer needs and provide actionable insights to solve pain points and drive customer value via customer journey mapping.

- Designed the information architect, coordinated launch communications, and deployed internal employee-facing SharePoint 365 sites for departments such as Claims, Underwriting, etc.
- Subject matter expert on customer experience trends, developing and sharing best practices and tactics to improve brand loyalty, satisfaction, retention, and growth.
- Serve as the voice of the customer to advocate for service-centric solutions that benefit consumers, partners, and agents.
- Perform root-cause analysis on functional issues and collaborate with tech partners and internal stakeholders to gather business requirements and see through to implementation.

STACKPATH, Mar 2018 - May 2018

#### **UI/UX DESIGNER**

- Created wireframes using Sketch & Invision for new aspects of the CDN portal from requirements.
- Conducted usability tests with customers to gather feedback and outline points for improvement.
- Facilitated customer interviews to review current implementations (continuous improvement).
- Utilized Zeplin to communicate design specs and handoff wireframes to development team.

THINK AGENCY, 2016 - 2018

## **UI Developer**

- Created fully functional webpages from mockups using CSS, HTML, JS, PHP, and MySQL.
- Created responsive designs from mockups while adhering to brand guidelines and web development best practices.
- Worked in a team environment to complete projects' tight deadlines.
- Updated legacy code that spanned across front-end and back-end functionality.
- Worked directly with clients to hear feedback and performed research to offer solutions and aid in creating user interface mockups fulfilling their needs and their customers' needs.

Universal Studios, Jan - Jun 2016

#### **IT-eCommerce Solutions Delivery Intern**

- Apprenticed with senior developers, reviewing code and digital content for universalorlando.com
- Contributed to a large, complex e-commerce project and worked with tools such as BitBucket.
- Used the agile methodology to work in a large, diverse team environment.

## **EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS**

- MASTER OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION (M.B.A. MARKETING), 2021; Saint Leo University
- BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.S. Web Design and Development) 2016; Full Sail University

## PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

- Toastmasters on the Halifax, Daytona Beach
- Volusia Young Professionals Group
- Omega Nu Lambda